Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
REASON FOR EXISTING, RAISON D'ÊTRE
THE REASON WHY ONE IS ALLOWED TO BE HERE
IN THE CASE OF SHINJI IKARI
THE BOY WISHED FOR DEATH OF HIS OWN WILL
THE BOY GRANTED HIS WISH
THE FINAL ANGEL IS GONE
BUT SHINJI IKARI IS TORMENTED
WHY DID YOU KILL HIM?
Because I had no choice!
Because Kaworu was... He was an Angel!
EVEN THOUGH HE WAS ALSO HUMAN?
No! An Angel! He was our enemy!
EVEN THOUGH HE WAS HUMAN, LIKE YOU?
No! No! You're wrong!
Even though he was a person, just like me?
No! He was an Angel!
That's why you killed him?
That's right! If I hadn't, we would've died!
Everyone would have been killed!
That's why you killed him?
I didn't do it because I wanted to!
I had no choice.
THAT'S WHY YOU KILLED HIM
Help me...
Help me.
THAT'S WHY YOU KILLED HIM
Help me!
Someone, help me!
THAT'S WHY YOU KILLED HIM
Please, someone just help me!
That's right, Kaworu was the one
who should have survived.
He was a much better person than I am.
Kaworu should have been the one to survive.
You're wrong.
Only those who have the will
to live get to survive.
He wished to die.
He abandoned his will to live,
clinging instead to a false hope.
You did nothing wrong, Shinji.
Is that true?
UNCERTAINTY
Is this really how it should be?
HAUNTING UNCERTAINTY
I don't know. What should I do?
What am I supposed to do?!
WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
Afraid of?
Me?
WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
Being hated.
By whom?
WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
By Father!
Father abandoned me! He hated me!
What will I do if people hate me?
What should I do?
Where am I?
Where am I supposed to go?
I can't see anything. I don't know what's what.
Miss Misato?
Miss Misato?!
Hey, where did you go, Miss Misato?
Hey, where am I supposed to go now?
Miss Misato! Asuka! Ayanami!
Toji! Kensuke! Miss Ritsuko!
Mr. Kaji!
Father!
Mother...
Someone tell me.
Tell me what I'm supposed to do.
Evangelion Unit 01...
So, do I ultimately have no choice
but to pilot it?
Even after killing someone I loved?
Are you saying I'm supposed to listen
to my father and everyone else,
and get back in this thing to fight?!
Mother!
Say something! Answer me!
WHY DO YOU PILOT THE EVA?
Because everyone tells me to pilot it.
THAT'S WHY YOU PILOT THE EVA?
It's... It's for the good of everybody,
so why does it matter?!
SO, YOU PILOT THE EVA FOR EVERYBODY,
FOR OTHERS?
That's right. It's a good thing!
It's a very good thing!
If I pilot it, everyone praises me!
They treat me well!
That's a lie!
What are you, stupid?!
In the end, you're just doing it for yourself!
And there you go, making up excuses
for yourself again!
I am?
Thinking that you're working hard
for the sake of others!
That in and of itself is the easy way to live!
Really?
In other words, you're lonely, Shinji.
That's just being dependent!
It's nothing but a symbiotic relationship!
You might be right.
You just want people to need you!
All you do is wait, wanting people
to give you happiness!
False happiness!
But that goes for you too.
THE SECOND CHARACTER
IN THE CASE OF ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
I don't remember getting on,
but I'm back in the Eva again.
I was put back in.
It's not going to move anyway, piece of junk.
No, I'm the piece of junk.
They don't need me! No one needs me!
No one needs a pilot who can't control her Eva!
So, you're seeking to find yourself in others.
Shut up!
SEPARATION ANXIETY
You're afraid of becoming alone, aren't you?
Because you disappear along with the people
around you. That's why you're afraid, aren't you?
SEPARATION ANXIETY
That's why you pilot the Eva!
ATTACHMENT BEHAVIOR
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
I don't want to hear that from a puppet like you!
THE THIRD CHARACTER
IN THE CASE OF REI AYANAMI
Who am I?
Rei Ayanami.
Who are you?
REI AYANAMI
You're also Rei Ayanami?
Yes, I am the thing that is called Rei Ayanami.
We are all things that are called Rei Ayanami.
How can we all be me?
Because everybody calls us Rei Ayanami.
Why do you possess a false heart and body?
They are not false, because I am me.
No, you are a person whose false soul was
created by the human named Gendo Ikari.
You're nothing but an object living a lie,
pretending to be a person.
See? There's a dark part
of your heart inside you
that you can see nothing of,
that you know nothing of.
That's where the real you is.
I am me.
Because I became who I am
through the time I've spent
and the connections I've made
with other people.
The current me has been molded
through contact with other people.
Contact with people and the passage of time
change the shape of my heart.
"IS THAT WHAT TIES ARE?"
Yes, the things that have created the me
called Rei Ayanami so far...
The things that will continue to shape me...
"THAT IS WHAT TIES ARE"
But the real you is somewhere else.
You just don't know it.
Because you don't want to see it.
You're just avoiding it without realizing it.
"BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID"
Because it may not be human in form.
Because the person that I have been
so far may cease to exist.
"YOU ARE AFRAID"
You're afraid of ceasing to exist.
You're afraid of being erased
from everyone's hearts.
Afraid?
I don't understand.
Your own individual world
will also cease to exist.
"IT FRIGHTENS YOU, DOESN'T IT?"
You will cease to exist.
No, it makes me happy.
Because I want to die.
What I desire is despair.
I want to return to nothingness.
But I can't.
I cannot return to nothingness.
He won't let me return.
He won't let me go back yet.
I existed because he needed me.
But it's over now.
He's not going to need me anymore.
He's going to abandon me.
I thought I had wished for
that day to come, but...
Now, I am afraid.
Come, let us go.
You have existed for this day, today, Rei.
Yes!
AND THEN...
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF MANKIND BEGINS
EPISODE 25
THE WORLD ENDING
ONCE AGAIN, SHINJI IKARI
What is this sensation?
I feel like I've experienced it before,
as if the shape of my body is melting away.
It feels so good.
I feel like I'm growing, expanding outward...
On and on...
THAT WAS THE BEGINNING OF THE
INSTRUMENTALITY OF PEOPLE
WHAT PEOPLE ARE LACKING
THE LOSS IN THEIR HEARTS
IN ORDER TO FILL THAT VOID IN THEIR HEARTS
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF HEARTS
AND SOULS BEGINS
RETURNING ALL THINGS TO NOTHINGNESS
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF PEOPLE HAD BEGUN
No, it is not that we are returning
to nothingness.
We are only restoring everything
to its original state.
We are only returning to our mother,
who has been lost to this world.
All souls will become one
and find eternal peace.
That is all there is to it.
And that's the Instrumentality Project?
That's right.
There is always a void, a part that
has been lost in our hearts.
THAT IS WHAT GIVES RISE TO THE
HUNGER IN OUR HEARTS
THIS IS WHAT GIVES RISE TO FEAR AND INSECURITY
Every single person fears that
darkness in their heart
and lives life trying to escape from it,
to banish it.
Even though it will never disappear
as long as we remain human.
That's why you're going to bundle
all human souls together,
so we can compensate for
the void in each other?!
And you're just going to do this to everyone?!
Mind your own business!
That's nothing more than
a conspiracy to deceive us!
But you've been wishing for it to happen too.
Where am I?
IN THE CASE OF MISATO KATSURAGI
This is the me that exists
in your mind, Miss Misato.
And at the same time, the me
that exists in your mind, right?
I must connect with all sorts of people
in order for me to find who I am.
I must search deep within myself.
I must search deep within the Miss Misato
that exists in my mind.
What is it that you want, Miss Misato?
"YOU WANT TO BE A GOOD GIRL?"
I have to be a good girl.
"WHY?"
Because my dad's not around.
I have to help my mom and be a good girl.
But I don't want to become like my mom,
because she's always crying
when my dad isn't here.
No crying, no being spoiled.
That's why I have to be a good girl.
And I'm going to do my best
so my dad won't hate me.
But I hate my father.
That's why I hate being good too.
I hate it all now.
And I'm so tired.
Of having to maintain my clean image.
Of myself, for keeping up this pretense
of being so pristine.
I'm just tired of it.
I want to be dirty.
I wanted to see what I looked like
when I was no longer perfect.
Is that why you slept with him? With that man?
No, I slept with him because I loved him.
Did you really love him?
Yes, I did.
He accepted me for who I am.
"REALLY?"
He was kind to me!
No! Stop it! Don't show this part of me to Shinji!
There's no reason to be embarrassed
after all that has happened.
It IS embarrassing!
Why is it embarrassing?
You have no problem...
no, you actually enjoy
presenting this side of yourself
to the man you love.
No! Please stop!
In all honesty, you are actually
happy to show this to Shinji.
That's a lie! You're wrong! Wrong!
I don't know about that.
You actually want to show this
to your father, don't you?
You're wrong!
You sought peace in Kaji's face as he slept.
You sought peace in Kaji's warmth.
You're wrong!
You sought your father in Kaji's arms.
It's not true!
That's right.
That time, I saw my own father in Kaji.
That's why I ran away from him.
I was scared.
It was as if he were my father and...
But it was actually because I was happy.
I derived pleasure from it.
It was a moment of unbearably
wonderful feeling.
That's why I hated it.
That's why I split up with him.
Well, I guess it just means love
begins for no reason,
but always ends for a reason.
You're so kind, Kaji.
Please take that kindness...
...and tarnish me with it.
Just because you hate yourself now
doesn't mean you should hurt yourself.
That's just fooling yourself into feeling better
by punishing yourself for the moment.
You should stop doing that.
And you're going to tell me
to be good to myself, right?
That's what all men are like.
And after that, they go off to work,
into their own worlds.
Leaving me behind...
Just like Father.
All I'm ever doing is running away
from the harsh reality.
Harsh reality?
That's me, isn't it?
Of course, just look at me.
It's only to be expected.
Stop it, Miss Misato!
Sometimes, I lose all hope for myself!
I hate it!
Filth, you're so dirty.
You're pathetic.
Disgusting! You're just foul!
That's what you call a mature relationship?!
You make me puke!
Congratulations on your promotion,
Major Katsuragi.
The person being recognized
is the me who's putting on a performance
in order to be recognized.
It's not the real me.
The real you is always crying.
No, I'm happy.
"AM I HAPPY?"
I'm happy.
I am happy!
"AM I HAPPY?"
No! This isn't happiness!
"WHAT IS HAPPINESS?"
This isn't the real me!
I've only made myself believe that it is!
Is that what we have to do to keep on living?
You're afraid when you're not together.
You're insecure.
Unless someone's sleeping by your side.
Are you scared of sleeping by yourself?
Are you lonely sleeping by yourself after all?
You can't bear the loss in your heart.
That's why you'll be with anyone,
it doesn't matter who.
That's not true!
No, you just want to give yourself
over to simple pleasure.
You just want to soothe your soul
through temporary escapes
and you're only using men to that end.
No! You're wrong! Wrong!
WHAT COULD IT BE THAT SHE WANTS?
Where am I?
This is the me that exists in your mind, Asuka.
Which means, it's also the me
that exists in your mind, right?
IN THE CASE OF ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
Asuka, what do you want?
I'm going to live on my own!
I don't need Mom or Dad.
I'm going to live by myself.
I'm not going to cry anymore.
But I'm still crying...
Why am I crying?
I don't know how to deal with that child.
What's this? You, a doctor, getting
discouraged? It isn't like you.
Even doctors are human,
as I have mentioned before.
But a woman like you having
trouble with a child...
She's oddly mature,
and there's a sense of vigilant
and absolute rejection.
It scares me sometimes.
Haven't you ever felt that way, dear?
No.
Anyway, you're Asuka's mother now.
But before that, I first became your wife.
You became both at the same time.
Yes, from a social standpoint, that's true.
But you can never stop being that child's father,
whereas I can quit being her mother at any time.
True enough.
Don't, Mom! Don't quit being my mom!
I'll be a good girl, so you'll like me!
So, don't quit being my mom!
So, look at me!
Stop, Mom!
Don't kill me!
Your dad doesn't love your mom anymore.
He doesn't need me.
No, he never loved me to begin with.
He probably didn't need me from the start.
So, die with me, because your dad
doesn't need us.
Am I a bother? Am I not needed?
Please die with me.
No! I'm not your doll, Mom!
I'll think for myself and live on my own!
That time, my mom was hanging
from the ceiling.
The expression on her face
looked very happy.
But I hated that look on her face.
I don't want to die. I don't want to disappear.
I hate boys. I hate Mom and Dad too!
I hate everybody!
No one will protect me.
No one will stay with me.
WHAT DOES SHE WANT?
That's why I'm going to live by myself.
But I don't want to! It's hard!
I don't want to be alone!
Don't forsake me.
Don't abandon me.
Don't kill me.
What is this?
The Human Instrumentality Project
that your father was working on.
This is?
It appears to be part of it.
Because the truth eludes even us.
Only what you can feel for yourself
right now is fact.
Within you.
And your memory of those things
will become the truth for you.
There are also some truths
that change with time.
So, this is fact, the result of everything
that was done. This...
There are a lot of realities.
This is one of them.
This is the result you wished for.
The one I wished for?
Yes, annihilation, a world
where no one is saved.
No! It's just that no one saved me! No one...
No one can save you.
This is what you wished for.
Destruction, death, the return to nothingness...
It's what you wished for.
This is reality.
What is reality?
It's your world.
It's your own world where you coexist
with time, space, and other people.
It's a world where you yourself decide
how to perceive and accept it.
Right now, this is your world,
where everything is given to you.
THAT IS REALITY
This is your world, which cannot be helped.
It's a world where everything's already set!
You're wrong. It's a world where
you make the decisions.
It's a world where your heart
has decided that it is so.
THIS IS REALITY
Your will to live...
Your thoughts of wanting to die...
They are all what you wished for.
You're saying even this darkness
and this world of half measures
are all things I wished for?
That's right.
You wished for a closed world,
where you alone are comfortable.
In order to protect the weakness of your heart.
In order to protect your pleasures in life.
This is merely the result.
For people cannot live in a world
that is yours alone.
They cannot live in a space
that is closed off.
But you wished for the world, the world
that surrounds you, to be closed off.
Your heart and mind eliminated
everything you didn't like
and wished for a world as solitary as possible.
And that has led to this little haven for your soul.
This is one of the many ends that could occur.
This is the end of the world
that you have brought about.
AND THE JOURNEY TOWARDS INSTRUMENTALITY...
...WILL CONTINUE
PREVIEW
The end, it is something that always
comes after the beginning.
Will our wishes lead to destruction?
Is our hope death itself?
Final episode: "The Beast That Shouted Love
at the Heart of the World"
FINAL EPISODE
THE BEAST THAT SHOUTED LOVE
AT THE HEART OF THE WORLD